Aditya Modi

1045 La Avenida St. Mountain View, CA-94043 (734) 881 0810 ⊠ adityamodi94@gmail.com adityamodi.github.io

Overview

I'm a machine learning researcher interested in general sequential decision making problems with a focus on the foundations and real-world applications of reinforcement learning. In general, my interests range from active learning to bandits, reinforcement learning and causal inference. Overall, my aim is to devise novel methods and advance our understanding of building AI agents which can augment and/or compete with human-level decision making, safely and reliably.

Education

Sept '16-Nov '21 PhD, Computer Science, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor,

Advisors: Satinder Singh and Ambuj Tewari.

Thesis: Provably Efficient Reinforcement Learning Under Linear Model Structures: From Tabular to Feature Based Exploration [link]

Aug '12- May '16

Bachelor of Technology, Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur, GPA – 9.4/10.0.

Major: Computer Science

Professional Experience

Nov '21-Present **Applied Scientist**, *Microsoft Ads*, Mountain View, CA.

Working on applied research problems on topics ranging from bandits and RL to causal inference to improve the advertising products at MS.

July-Oct 2018 Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Redmond.

Optimizing modular software pipelines via Reinforcement Learning

Mentors: Debadeepta Dev. Eric Horvitz

Worked on the application of contextual bandit, learning to search and policy search methods to input-adaptive parameter/algorithm selection across components in any modular software pipeline. Work published in AAAI 2020.

Sept-Dec 2016 **Research Assistant**, *University of Michigan*, Ann Arbor.

Data-dependent Importance weighted Active Learning

Advisors: Ambuj Tewari and Barzan Mozafari

Studied the sample complexity of importance-weighted active learning (IWAL) algorithms based on data-dependent complexity measures for bounded loss functions.

May-July 2015 Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Bangalore, India.

Active Semi-supervised Performance Evaluation

Advisor: Sundararajan Sellamanickam, Principal Applied Scientist.

[Report]

Proposed an estimation method for performance measures of black-box classifiers using scarcely labelled datasets for various non-decomposable performance measures (ROC curve, PR curve, F-measure).

Publications/Preprints

(Google scholar profile)

Preprint On the Statistical Efficiency of Reward-free Exploration in Non-linear Reinforcement Learning.

Jinglin Chen*, Aditya Modi*, Akshay Krishnamurthy, Nan Jiang, Alekh Agarwal In submission.

[link coming soon]

Preprint Multi-task Learning of Linear Control Systems under Instability.

Aditya Modi, Ziping Xu, Mohamad Kazem Shirani Faradonbeh, Ambuj Tewari In submission.

[link coming soon]

Preprint Joint Learning-Based Stabilization of Multiple Unknown Linear Systems. Mohamad Kazem Shirani Faradonbeh, Aditya Modi [arxiv] IFAC Workshop on Adaptive Learning and Control Systems (ALCOS), 2022. Preprint Joint Learning of Linear Time-Invariant Dynamical Systems. Aditya Modi, Mohamad Kazem Shirani Faradonbeh, Ambuj Tewari, George Michailidis [arxiv] Preprint Model-Free Representation Learning and Exploration in Low-rank MDPs. Aditya Modi*, Jinglin Chen*, Akshay Krishnamurthy, Nan Jiang, Alekh Agarwal [arxiv] In submission. ICML 2020 Clinician-in-the-Loop Decision Making: Reinforcement Learning with Near-Optimal Set-Valued Shengpu Tang, Aditya Modi, Michael Sjoding, Jenna Wiens [link] International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2020. UAI 2020 No-regret Exploration in Contextual Reinforcement Learning. Aditya Modi and Ambuj Tewari [link] Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI), 2020 Abridged version accepted to ICML 2019 wkshp on RL for Real Life and RLDM 2019. AISTATS 2020 Sample Complexity of Reinforcement Learning with Linearly Combined Model Ensembles. Aditya Modi, Nan Jiang, Ambuj Tewari, Satinder Singh [link] International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS), 2020. AAAI 2020 Meta-Reasoning in Modular Software Systems via Reinforcement Learning. A. Modi, D. Dey, A. Agarwal, A. Swaminathan, B. Nushi, S. Andrist, E. Horvitz [link] AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2020 Invited poster at ICML 2019 Workshop on Reinforcement Learning for Real Life ALT 2018 Markov Decision Processes with Continuous Side Information. Aditya Modi, Nan Jiang, Satinder Singh, Ambuj Tewari [link] International Conference on Algorithmic Learning Theory (ALT) 2018 * Equal contribution Scholastic Achievements 2019-20 NeurIPS 2019, 2020 and ICML 2020 best reviewer award. 2013, 2015 Academic Excellence Award, IIT Kanpur. 2014 Ram Parkash Chopra Memorial Scholarship, given for academic excellence, IIT Kanpur. 2013-15 Honourable mention in ACM ICPC Asia Amritapuri (2014-15, 2013-14) and Kanpur regionals (2013-14). 2013 O.P. Jindal Engineering and Management scholarship (awarded to select few candidates from top eng. and

- - management institutes in India)

Talks/Presentations

June 2021 Contextual Reinforcement Learning: Learning optimal intervention policies for a heterogeneous population.

Canadian Operations Research Society (CORS) annual conference, 2021

March 2021 Model-free Representation Learning and Exploration in Low-rank MDPs.

RL Theory virtual seminar series.

March 2019 Contextual Decision Processes using Generalized Linear Models.

Speed Oral and poster, Mich. Student Symp. on Interdisciplinary Statistical Sciences (MSSISS) 2019

March 2018 Markov Decision Processes with Continuous Side Information.

Oral presentation, Mich. Student Symp. on Interdisciplinary Statistical Sciences (MSSISS) 2018

[Link]

Teaching experience

- Winter 2017 Graduate Student Instructor, EECS 445 Machine Learning, Univ. of Michigan.
- Winter 2016 Student Mentor, CS 771 Machine Learning Techniques, IIT Kanpur.
 - Fall 2015 **Teaching Assistant**, ESO 207 Data Structures and Algorithms, IIT Kanpur.

Professional Services and Participation

Program Com-	AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence	2019
mittee/reviewer	Conference on Artifical Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS)	2019-22
	Conference on Algorithmic Learning Theory	2020
	International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)	2019-22 (2020*)
	Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	2019-22 (2019,20*)
	Conference on Uncertainty in AI (UAI)	2022
	International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	2021-22
	IEEE Transactions on Information Theory	2022
	Conference on Lifelong Learning Agents (CoLLAs)	2022
	Theoretical Foundations of RL, ICML	2020
	Deep Reinforcement Learning workshops (NeurIPS)	2020-21
	Workshop on RL Theory (ICML)	2021

^{*} Top reviewer award

- Fall '20 Long term participant in Simons Institute' (UC Berkeley) program on Theory of Reinforcement Learning
- April 2018 Participant in 2nd Center for Human-Compatible AI (CHAI) annual workshop.

European Workshop on Reinforcement Learning (EWRL)

2017, 2018 Co-organizer, Statistical Machine Learning Reading group, Univ. of Michigan.

2022.